

# Donald McLamb

Full-Stack Web Developer & Cyber Security Professional

#### Contact Me:



443.677.8501



mclamb.donald@gmail.com



www.cyberdesigns.io

## **Primary Skills:**









# Other Technical Skills:

#### Management & Other IT Skills

- PostgreSQL
- Foundations
- Github
- AWS
- Heroku
- Microsoft Server 2012

#### Cybersecurity ToolsHelix

- Kal
- Snort
- Nmap
- Wireshark

### Methodologies & Processes

- Agile Design
- Entity Relational Diagram
- MVC
- Wire framing

#### Misc. Software

- Image Editing Software
- Bash
- Vim
- Atom

## Overview

A skilled full-stack developer and cybersecurity professional dedicated to the safety and security of information as well as the user experience. Seasoned problem solver with a strong drive to develop useful, secure applications and software that promote solutions to relevant security concerns.

# **Industry Experience and Projects**

Cyberdesigns.io, Gaithersburg MD, June 2015 - Present

A freelance company I started to continue the development of my portfolio.

DayTrackr - daytrackr.meteor.com, June 2015 - Present

A individual project, currently in a prototype state using Meteor.js. It is mobile compatibile and responsive. The end result will be a multi-platform scheduler and alarm app.

Technologies used: Meteor.js, HTML, CSS, Foundations

#### General Assembly, Washington DC, March 2015 - June 2015

WDI student at a full-stack web development program focused on common best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development. Developed a portfolio of individually focused and collaboratively focused projects.

SecurityPulse - <u>securitypulse.herokuapp.com</u>, May 2015 - May 2015
A individual project that was developed to centralizing cyber security information while also providing a resource for people to discuss cybersecurity issues.

Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, Pry, ActiveRecord, PostgresSQL, CanCanCan, Devise, HTML, CSS

WritersHub - the-writers-hub.herokuapp.com, June 2015 - June 2015 A group project that allows unpublished writers to receive feedback to improve their work and allow readers to review work from up and coming authors.

Techologies used: Ruby, RoR, PostgresSQL, HTML,CSS, Foundations

**DC Science Hackathon, Washington DC,** *March 2015 - March 2015* A 2-day event to develop something creative and impactful while collaborating.

PoliConnect - policonnect.org, March 2015 - Present

A group project for a DC Science Hackathon, the app's function is to connect policy makers to experts anonymously so that productive debates can take place.

• Strategized security and anonymity solutions.

Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, PostgresSQL, CanCanCan, FFaker, AWS

## **Employment History**

Axxis Software, Gaithersburg MD, May 2013 - April 2015

Software Support Engineer

- Supported customers, IT staff and performed server migrations
- Reviewed and analyzed system logs to find environmental issues
- Advised on security practices, server configuration

#### Motionsoft, Rockville MD, April 2012 - May 2013

Software Support Engineer

- Implemented and trained customers on CMS systems
- Troubleshooted hand key scanners, control access systems
- Executed SQL queries to troubleshoot issues

#### Education

**Codementors - Online**, June 2015 - August 2015 Angular JS Online Course

**General Assembly - Washington DC,** June 2015 Web Development Immersive Course

**UMUC - Adelphi, Maryland,** December 2015 Masters of Science - Cybersecurity

**Towson University - Towson MD,** December 2010 Bachelors of Science - Sociology & Psychology